kcchiefs.com 2015-11-15

# Privacy and Security Statement

**The Kansas City Chiefs Football Club Privacy Policy**

<http://www.kcchiefs.com/privacy-policy.html>

**Effective: April 2, 2014**

This privacy policy applies to the Kansas City Chiefs websites, including the site located at www.kcchiefs.com (the "Website"), the Kansas City Chiefs mobile application(s) (the “App”), and all other electronic services, websites, or applications offered by the Kansas City Chiefs for their fans. The Website, the App, and any other services are referred to collectively herein as the Services. The purpose of this privacy policy is to disclose to you what information we may collect, how we may collect it, with whom we may share it, and certain other matters related to such information, including the choices you have regarding our collection of information and our use and disclosure to other parties of information we may have collected from you. 

The Website is owned by the Kansas City Chiefs Football Club, Inc. (the “Club”, “we”, “our”, or “us”). We have contracted with various third party service providers to operate and manage specific sections or applications of the Services on our behalf including the App, the Chiefs Pro Shop at shop.kcchiefs.com, the Chiefs Kids Club, and certain other applications or segments of the Services provided to you by the Chiefs (the “Contracted Applications”) that may provide additional privacy policies and practices with respect to information you provide through such Contracted Applications. In particular, the Chiefs Kids Club, and any information collected through the Chiefs Kids Club, is governed by a separate privacy policy as outlined below. Unless otherwise stated, we own the information collected via the Services and we may use it for our own business purposes, including marketing.

The Club has received TRUSTe's Privacy Seal signifying that this privacy statement and our practices have been reviewed for compliance with the TRUSTe program viewable on the validation page available by clicking the TRUSTe seal.

The TRUSTe program covers only information that is collected through this Web site www.kcchiefs.com and does not cover information that may be collected through our mobile applications. 

**If you have questions or complaints regarding our privacy policy or practices please contact us at customerrelations@kcchiefs.com.** ** ** If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact TRUSTe at <https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request>.

When this privacy policy uses the term "personally identifiable information" or "personal information," we mean information that identifies a particular individual, such as your full name, street address, social media account name, or email address. When other information, such as a favorite team, player, or your seat location, is associated with personal information, it also becomes personally identifiable information for the purposes of this privacy policy. 

Please read the information below to learn more about our data collection policies and practices.

  * Types Of Information That May Be Collected
  * How Information May Be Collected
  * How We Use The Information Collected
  * With Whom The Information May Be Shared
  * Links To Other websites
  * Security
  * Data Retention
  * Chat Rooms, Forums, and Message Boards
  * Your Acceptance Of This Privacy Policy And Notification Of Changes To This Policy
  * Correcting/Updating Personal Information
  * Your California Privacy Rights
  * Questions About This Privacy Policy

### **Types Of Information That May Be Collected**

The following are the types of information we may collect through the Services:

**Information You Provide Us** : In the course of using the Services, we may ask you to provide us with certain information, including contact information, such as your name, mailing address, seat location, user ID, user password, geolocation, email address, social media information, phone number, or fax number, unique identifiers, your demographic information: such as your date of birth, age, gender, education, household income, occupation, ticket holder status, game attendance, home ownership, marital status, or number of children, financial information, such as your credit card number or similar information.

**Site Usage Information** : We may receive and store certain types of usage information whenever you visit the Services, such as your click-stream data and your IP address or device ID. (See “Persistent Identifiers and Click Stream Data” section below)

**Email Communications** : When you open emails from us, we may receive a confirmation notifying us that you opened the email, if your computer supports such capabilities. We also may keep track of what emails we send you and what emails you may be receiving from our subsidiaries and affiliates. Additionally, we keep a record of what communications you have subscribed to receive or not to receive. If you would like to opt-out of receiving such emails, please click on the "unsubscribe" link in the email and follow the instructions.

**Information from Other Sources** : We may receive information about you (e.g., missing street number) from other sources, including commercial sources, and add it to your personal information.

How Information May Be Collected

We may collect information from you in several different areas through the Services, including but not limited to those described below:

**Registration:** You may be asked to complete a registration form and provide personally identifiable information; you may also be asked to choose a user ID and password in order to take advantage of certain features the Services may offer, such as newsletters, contests, stadium amenity maps, or social media integration. Your decision to register is voluntary and you will have the opportunity to decide whether or not to disclose information to us and what communications you would like to receive; however, please be advised that many products and services available on the Services require registration and if you elect not to provide such information, you will not be able to take advantage of those products and services.

**Newsletters and Emails:** We offer free newsletters to share information with you about the Services, about us and our affiliates and subsidiaries, or about our marketing partners and advertisers and sponsors. You may receive a newsletter either by registering for a particular newsletter or in conjunction with a special feature or membership for which you have registered on the Services. Participation is voluntary and you will have the opportunity to decide whether or not to disclose information to the Services. You may also cancel your free email subscription by following the instructions provided on the Website, in the App, or in the newsletter or email.

**Tell-A-Friend:**  If you choose to use our referral service to tell a friend about season tickets, we will ask you for your friend’s name and email address. We may send your friend a one-time email inviting him or her to visit the site. Kansas City Chiefs stores this information for the sole purpose of sending an email and tracking the success of our referral program. Your friend may contact us at <http://www.kcchiefs.com/contact-us.html> to request that we remove this information from our database.

**Contests or Sweepstakes:** We periodically operate contests and sweepstakes through the Services that may require registration or the submission of personal information. Participation is voluntary and you will have the opportunity to decide whether or not to disclose information to the Services. Your personally identifiable information may be used to contact you for winner notification, prize delivery confirmation or other related purposes, (see the rules of each contest for details about how your personal information will be used).

**Surveys or Voting:** From time-to-time we may request personally identifiable information from you in conjunction with a survey or voting poll. Participation is voluntary and you will have the opportunity to decide whether or not to disclose information to the Services. Our fan polls are anonymous and do not collect any personal information.

**Location Data:** If you use a device with a Global Positioning System ("GPS") or other location detection functionality, then we may collect precise information about the location of your device during your use of our sites and applications. We may use your location information to provide any requested location services and we may provide alternate functionality in your use of our sites and applications based on your location. You may opt-out from further allowing us to have any access to your location data by disabling your device's location detection functionality or GPS system.

**Games:** When you register to play games on the Services, you may be asked to provide personally identifiable information.

**Cookies:** As with many websites and apps, our Services use a technology called "cookies." A cookie is a collection of information that gets stored on the hard drive of your computer when browsing the Internet. These small bits of code automatically identify your browser to the Website whenever your computer is used to visit or use the Services. Cookies automatically identify your browser to the Services whenever your device is used with the Services. Cookies also let us know how many times a user has been on certain pages and where visitors go on the Website and App. In addition, cookies can let us know non-personally identifiable information, like what web browser or operating system is being used to access the Services. For registered users, cookies can make using the Services easier for you by saving information such as your passwords or preferences. By tracking how and when you use the Services, cookies help us determine which areas are popular and which are not. Many improvements and updates to the Services are based on data obtained from cookies. Accepting cookies allows you, among other things, to personalize your experience on the Services. Cookies may also allow the Services to present to you advertising which may be of interest to you. If you do not want information collected through the use of cookies, your browser should contain an option that allows you to disable or delete cookie data at any time. Some areas of the Services, however, may not provide you with a personalized experience if you have disabled the use of cookies. You can opt out of some, but not all, third-party advertiser cookies in one location at the Network Advertising Initiative opt-out website, located at [www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp). You may block all browser cookies by following the instructions applicable to your browser at <http://www.aboutcookies.org/page-1>.

**Third Party Cookies:** The use of cookies by our tracking utility company, and service providers are not covered by our privacy statement. We do not have access or control over these cookies. Our tracking utility company and service providers use session ID cookies to make it easier for you to navigate our site, in order for you to use the shopping cart, etc.

**Web beacons and Other Tracking Technology:** Our Services use a variety of technical methods for tracking purposes, including Web beacons. Web beacons are small pieces of data that are embedded in images on the pages of websites. We also use these technical methods to analyze the traffic patterns on the Services, such as the frequency with which our users visit various parts of the Services. These technical methods may involve the transmission of information either directly to us or to another party authorized by us to collect information on our behalf. We also use these technical methods in HTML emails that we send to determine whether the recipients have opened those emails and/or clicked on links in those emails. The information from use of these technical methods may be collected in a form that is personally identifiable.

**Persistent Identifiers and Click-Stream Data:** We may collect persistent identifiers and/or click-stream data. Persistent identifiers include device IDs and IP addresses. A device ID is a number associate with a particular device that can identify that device across multiple visits. An IP address is a number associated with the service through which you access the Internet, like your ISP (Internet service provider), your company, or your university. Standing alone, your IP address or device ID is not personally identifiable. At times, we also use such persistent identifiers for purposes of system administration and to report aggregate information to our advertisers and sponsors, for example regarding the frequency with which our guests visit various parts of our sites. We may combine this information with personally identifiable information we obtain from you directly through the Services or otherwise, including from third parties.

Click-stream data is information collected by our computers when you request data from the Services. Click-stream data may include such information as the data served, the time, the source of the request, the type of device or browser making the request, the preceding page view and other such non-personal information. When analyzed, this data helps us analyze how visitors arrive, what type of content is most popular, what type of visitors in the aggregate are interested in particular kinds of content and advertising.

**Transaction Information:** If you conduct any transaction with the Services, such as such as ordering information, buying our products, or subscribing to programs offered through the Services, we will ask you to complete an order form that will request certain information from you, including contact information, demographic information and financial information. In some instances, we may direct you to a third party vendor site to collect this information from you directly. Even though the collection form may have the look and feel of the Website or other Services provided by the Club, please be aware you will be giving your information directly to the third party vendor, and that, generally in such instances, such third party vendor's privacy policy will govern the collection of your personal information. Please reference the privacy policies available from these pages for any privacy related concerns.

We and/or our vendor will use this information to complete the transaction that you have requested, i.e. to deliver the information, products or other services that you request or purchase, to invoice you, and in a manner consistent with this Privacy Policy. For your protection, financial information you provide through the Services is collected and stored through encrypted means.

### **How We Use the Information Collected**

We own the information collected on or through the Services. As applicable, the information you provide to us may be used to:

  * contact you about the Services;
  * provide you with services or information you have requested or products or services you have ordered, such as subscription plans or other products and services;
  * contact you relating to your membership status;
  * confirm or fulfill an order you have made;
  * inform you of a prize you have won or been deemed a finalist for;
  * monitor or improve the use of the Services;
  * customize the advertising and content you see;
  * monitor compliance with the terms and conditions of use of the Services, as applicable; and
  * send you promotional materials or special offers on our behalf or on behalf of our marketing partners and/or their respective affiliates and subsidiaries and other third parties.

### **With Whom The Information May Be Shared**

At times, as described below we may share your personal information with others for various purposes.

**Agents:** We employ other businesses, certain services and individuals to perform functions on our behalf. Examples include fulfilling orders, sending e-mail, publishing and maintaining the App, removing repetitive information from customer lists, Website and App analysis, analyzing data, providing marketing assistance, processing credit card payments, and providing customer service. We may frame pages within certain sections of the site (examples include: the Pro Shop and ticket purchases) that will have the look and feel of the Website or App; however, please be aware that you are entering your information on 3rd party agent websites and not directly to the Club. The Third Parties in such integrated situations may have access to personally identifiable information needed to perform their functions, but may not use or disclose it for their own purposes, like sending you marketing offers about their products.

**Aggregate or De-Identified Information:** We may share aggregate or de-identified information, such as demographics and usage statistics, with advertisers, sponsors or other organizations other parties that we partner with from time to time. When this type of information is shared, the other parties do not have access to your personally identifiable information.

**Social Media:** Our Web site includes Social Media Features, such as the Facebook Like button [and Widgets, such as the Share this button or interactive mini-programs that run on our site]. These Features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.

**Option to Receive Third Party Offers:** Throughout the Services you may be presented with an opportunity to receive information and/or marketing offers sent from third party(s). Such opportunities will give you the choice to share your personally identifiable information with such third party(s) as necessary to receive such information or marketing offers. If you do not elect to have your personally identifiable information shared, your personally identifiable information will not be shared with such third party(s). If you do choose to have your personally identifiable information shared, your personally identifiable information will be transferred to such third party(s) solely for the purpose of permitting such third party(s) to provide you with such information and marketing offers. Such third party(s) is/are not authorized by us to disclose your personally identifiable information to any other third parties. Please be advised that if you elect to provide your personally identifiable information in response to such third party(s) marketing offers or otherwise, all information you disclose to such third party(s) will be subject to the privacy policy and practices of such third party(s). We are not responsible for the privacy practices and policies of such third party(s) and, therefore, you should review the privacy practices and policies of such third party(s) prior to providing your personally identifiable information to such third party(s).

**Products or Services Offered in Partnership with Third-Party(s):** Certain products and/or services may appear to be available from the Club but are actually provided to you in partnership with third party(s) and may require you to disclose personally identifiable information in order to register for and access such products and/or services, including the App. Such products and/or services shall identify the third party partners prior to or at the point of registration. If you elect to register for such products and/or services your personally identifiable information will be transferred to such third party(s) and will be subject to the privacy policy and practices of such third party(s). We are not responsible for the privacy practices and policies of such third party(s) and, therefore, you should review the privacy practices and policies of such third party(s) prior to providing your personally identifiable information in connection with such products and/or services.

**Subsidiaries and Affiliates:** We may share your information (including, without limitation, personally identifiable information) with all members of the Club’s family, including, without limitation, our subsidiaries and other affiliated entities with your prior consent to do so.

**Third-Party Ad Serving and Audience and Traffic Measurement Services:** We may use a third-party network advertiser to serve the advertisements on the Services or may use a traffic measurement service to analyze the traffic on the Services. Network advertisers are third parties that display advertisements based on your visits or use of the Services and other websites you have visited. Third-party ad serving enables us to target advertisements to you for products or websites you might be interested in. Audience and traffic measurement services allow us to collect anonymous traffic and behavior information from the Services by monitoring anonymous visitor activity. Although advertisers or other companies do not have access to the Services’ cookies, the advertisers, sponsors and/or traffic measurement services may themselves set and access their own cookies on your computer if you choose to have your cookies enabled in your browser. Cookies allow third-party advertisers to show you advertisements or content you might be interested in. Note that any images (or any other parts of a web page) served by third parties in association with third-party cookies may serve as web beacons, which enable third parties to carry out the previously described activities. Other companies' uses of their cookies are subject to their own privacy policies, not this one. Please visit <http://www.networkadvertising.org/optout_nonppii.asp> in order to learn more about the information collection practices and "opt-out" procedures of third-party ad servers we may use. You may block all browser cookies by following the instructions applicable to your browser at <http://www.aboutcookies.org/page-1>.

**Business Transfers:** In the event that all or substantially all of our assets are sold or transferred to another party, or another transaction occurs in which your personally identifiable information is one of the business assets transferred, all personally identifiable information that has been collected and saved may be one of the business assets we transfer, you will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on our Web site of any change in ownership or uses of your personal information, as well as any choices you may have regarding your personal information. Please see “Your Acceptance Of This Privacy Policy And Notification Of Changes To This Policy” below.

**E-mail Deployment:** We may share email activity data with our agents to help such agents better target email deployments sent on behalf of us and such agent's other clients. While such third party may have access to your email addresses and email activity, and may share bulk/non-specific activity data with third parties, no email addresses or specific email activity will be shared. If you wish to opt out of this sharing, please opt-out of receiving emails from us by clicking on the "unsubscribe" link in the email and following the instructions.

**Administrative or Legal Process:** We or others may disclose your personal information may be transferred to third parties without notice to you in order to comply with applicable law, such as to comply with a subpoena, law enforcement agencies, to protect our or third parties’ rights, or to protect the rights of other users of the Services.

### **Links to Other Websites or Apps**

You should be aware that when you use the Services you could be directed to other websites or applications beyond our control. For example, if you "click" on a banner advertisement, the "click" may take you off the Services onto different websites or apps. This includes links from advertisers, sponsors and marketing partners that may use the Club’s logo as part of a co-branding agreement. These other websites may send their own cookies to you, independently collect data or solicit personal information and may or may not have their own published privacy policies. If you visit a website that is linked to our Services, you should consult that website's privacy policy before providing any personal information.

### **Security**

The Services incorporate commercially reasonable safeguards to protect the security, integrity, completeness, accuracy and privacy of the personal information that we may collect and we have put into place reasonable precautions to protect such information from loss, misuse and alteration. Only those employees who need access to your information in order to do their jobs are allowed access. Our security policies are reviewed periodically and revised as required. We may permanently delete or destroy any and all personal information at any time as determined by us.

### **Data Retention**

We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services or as long as permitted under applicable law. If you wish to cancel your account or request that we no longer use your information to provide you services contact us at the address below. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

### **Chat Rooms, Forums, and Message Boards**

The Services may make chat rooms, forums, commenting and message boards available to you and other users. You are not required to provide any personal information when using these areas but you may choose to do so. If you post personal information online, it will be publicly available and you may receive unsolicited messages from other parties. In addition, when you post a comment on the App, the user name with which you registered for the Services and your current location may be made publicly available on the Website, the App, or otherwise through the Services. By using the commenting features of the Services, you acknowledge that your user name, location information, and any information you provide in the body of such comment may be disclosed to the public. We cannot ensure the security of any information you choose to make public in a chat room, forum, or message board. Also, we cannot ensure that parties who have access to such publicly available information will respect your privacy. Please exercise caution when deciding to disclose personal information in these areas. To request removal of your personal information from our blog or community forum, contact us at the address set below. In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why.

### **Your Acceptance Of This Privacy Policy And Notification Of Changes To This Policy**

By using the Services, you signify your agreement to the terms of our privacy policy. We may amend this privacy policy at any time. If we make a material change to the way in which we collect, use, and/or share your personal information, we will post a prominent notice on the Services and / or send an email to users who have provided an email address prior to the change becoming effective.  We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices.

### **Correcting/Updating Personal Information**

If your personally identifiable information changes (such as your email address or zip code), or if you no longer desire to access the Services, we will endeavor to provide a way to correct, update, delete  or remove the personal data you have provided to us. This can be done by making changes to your profile, by using an opt out message in an email, or by emailing us at [customerrelations@kcchiefs.com](mailto:customerrelations@kcchiefs.com).

### **Your California Privacy Rights**

California Civil Code Section 1798.83 permits customers of the Club who are California residents to request certain information regarding our disclosure of personal information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes. To make such a request, please send an email to [CAPrivacy@kcchiefs.com](mailto:CAPrivacy@kcchiefs.com) or write to us at The University of Kansas Hospital Training Complex | ATTN: CA Privacy Rights |1 Arrowhead Drive | Kansas City, MO 64129.

### **Questions About This Privacy Policy**

If you have any questions about this privacy policy or our privacy practices, contact [customerrelations@kcchiefs.com](mailto:customerrelations@kcchiefs.com) or write to us at The University of Kansas Hospital Training Complex | ATTN: Chiefs Privacy Policy |1 Arrowhead Drive | Kansas City, MO 64129.
